Guide to the Janet G. Travell papers, 1910-1997 MS0704.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Conferences, symposiums, and lectures, 1946-1995; MS0704 Series 1; 8 Linear feet (Box 11, Box 12, Box 13, Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 16, Box 17, Box 4, Box 3, Box 6, Box 5, Box 14, Box 15, Box 2, Box 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: The American Denture Society - notes on paper presented, 09/11/1959 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: The American Institute of Oral Biology, 11/02/1984 -11/06/1984 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Therapy Conference on Low Back Pain, 01/17/1941 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Therapy Conference on Low Back Pain, 05/18/1950 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Conferences, Lectures: TMJ Symposium, Orlando, FL, 03/27/1988 -03/31/1988 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Tobacco Industry Research Committee - Grantees Symposium on Nicotine, 1956 -1959 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Trigger Point Myotherapist Convention, Plymouth, MA, 10/10/1991 -10/13/1991 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Tri-State Institute of Traditional Chinese Acupuncture lecture "The Enigma of Myofascial Trigger Point Pain," Stanford, CT, 05/02/1992 -05/03/1992 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Conferences, Lectures: UCLA Lecture on headaches, 03/05/1976 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Conferences, Lectures: UCLA Pain Management Center lecture, 04/11/1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Uniformed Services Academy of Family Physicians meeting, Ft. Belvoir, VA, 03/18/1985 -03/25/1985 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of California at Los Angeles seminar on Low Back Pain, 05/14/1982 -05/15/1982 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of California Medical Center conferences, San Francisco, 11/15/1963 -11/17/1963 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Maryland Skeletal Muscular Pain lecture, 03/13/1964 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Maryland-Baltimore lecture, 03/18/1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Miami lectures, 10/11/1979 -10/14/1979 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Missouri-Kansas City address, 09/1976 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of New England, Biddford, Maine, 04/19/1982 -04/21/1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, NM, Chronic Myofascial Pain Syndromes, 10/12/1992 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Oregon Dental School lecture, 09/29/1978 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California Dental School lecture, 05/03/1975 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California Dental School seminars, Hawaii, 07/02/1977 -07/09/1977 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California Manipulative Medicine conference, 04/29/1977 -05/02/1976 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California Pain Symposium, 05/03/1975 -05/04/1975 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California School of Dentistry lectures, 10/26/1974 -10/27/1974 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California School of Dentistry lecture, 04/30/1977 -05/01/1977 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California School of Dentistry lectures, 04/28/1979 -04/29/1979 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California School of Dentistry meeting (canceled), 05/03/1980 -05/04/1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California School of Medicine meeting, Hawaii, 09/01/1979 -09/08/1979 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Southern California. Myofascial Pain symposium, 03/06/1976 -03/07/1976 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 02/04/1971 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lectures, 09/25/1972 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lectures, 09/25/1972 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 10/01/1973 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 11/04/1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 11/22/1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 12/13/1977 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 11/13/1978 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 11/16/1979 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 11/24/1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 11/16/1981 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Dental School lecture, 11/08/1982 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of Texas-Houston Health Science Center lecture, 04/07/1984 -04/09/1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, Lectures: University of the Pacific, School of Dentistry lecture "Myofascial Pain: Diagnosis and Management,", 01/14/1983 -01/15/1983 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Conferences, Lectures: USAF School of Aerospace Medicine lecture, San Antonio, TX, 04/24/1964 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Conferences, Lectures: USAF School of Medicine lecture, San Antonio, TX, 04/1966 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Veterans Admin. Hospital lecture, Long Beach, CA, 01/22/1982 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Veterans Administration Hospital lecture, Houston, TX, 02/05/1971 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Veterans Administration Hospital lecture, Houston, TX, 11/23/1976 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Virchow Society speech, 1957 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Virginia Osteopathic Medical Association conference, Williamsburg, VA, 05/14/1971 -05/15/1971 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Visual Training Conference, Washington, DC, 02/09/1969 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Volunteer Services Conference, Arlington, VA, 04/05/1965 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Walter Reed Army Medical Center lecture, Washington, DC, 05/22/1991 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Washington DC General Hospital lecture, 04/21/1970 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Washington Wellesley Club Spring Tea talk, Washington, DC, 05/17/1969 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Washington, DC Sanitarium, 06/18/1970 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Washington-Baltimore Physical Medicine meeting, 10/19/1967 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Conferences, Lectures: West Central Dental Society meeting, 10/27/1994 -10/29/1994 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Conferences, Lectures: White House Conference on Health, 11/03/1965 -11/04/1965 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Wilson Center seminar, Washington, DC, 10/17/1979 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Conferences, Lectures: "Women in Medicine" seminar at Westover School, Middlebury, CT, 06/04/1964 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Wyandotte General Hospital conference, Detroit, Michigan (location changed to Henry Ford Hospital), 03/05/1981 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Conferences, Lectures: Zohn, David A. - lecture, 10/26/1981 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Papers, manuscripts, reports and subject research, 1930-1994; MS0704 Series 2; 10 Linear feet (Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 37, Box 32, Box 18, Box 31, Box 19, Box 30, Box 20, Box 17, Box 21, Box 22, Box 36, Box 23, Box 35, Box 24, Box 34, Box 25, Box 33)
  This series consists of reports and papers written by Dr. Travell and the subject areas in which she did research. The material covers the dates 1930-94. This series also includes documents related to patient charts recording treatment for pain (names have been deleted), seat and chair design, and Ethyl Chloride Spray. Additional subject areas for Dr. Travell's research include air pollution, cardiac pain, exercise, hiccups, leg and foot pain, mental retardation, myofascial trigger areas, pain theories, procaine, stiff neck, and vertigo. Dr. Travell also did work with the Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation and its director Frank Fremont-Smith.
  - Reports, Subject Research: Abdominal TA's, 1961-1963 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Absorption - Antacids and Vitamin C, 1969-1972 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Absorption of nicotine - reading version, 1960 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Abstract of NY State paper "Hypometabolic Syndrome and Skeletal Muscle Pain,", 02/18/1957 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: ACTH and Andrenocotico Hormones, 1949-1953 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Acupuncture, 1989-1992 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Adjunct Analgesics, 1947-1957 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Adrenal Cortex - notes and references, 1962-1967 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Adrenal Function and Vitamin C, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Aerosols, 1969-1971 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Air Pollution, 1941-1960 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Alcoholism, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Amebiasis, 1936-1951 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: American Geriatrics Society, 1959 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: American Rheumatism Association, 1955-1959 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Anaesthesia and Sprains, 1942-1950 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Anaesthetics and Anaesthesia, 1952 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Anatomical photos and drawings of the leg, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Anatomy- Sacroiliac joint, 1941-1967 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Animals Which Do Not Make Vitamin C, 1954-1973 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ankle Sprains, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Antacids, 1938-1941 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Antibiotics, 1952-1953 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Arsenic and Antimony, 1936-1944 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ascorbic Acid and Iron, 1964-1972 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ascorbic Acid and Mental Disease, 1970-1971 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ascorbic Acid and Smoking, 1952-1972 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ascorbic Acid Studies and the Military, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Assessment of Drugs for Therapeutic Efficacy" by Janet Travell, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Atypical Facial Neuralgia" by Janet Travell, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Back problems, 1976-1980 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Barbiturate, 1944-1954 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Basis for Multiple Uses of Local Block of Somatic Trigger Areas" by Janet Travell, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Beds and mattresses, 1940-1954 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Bicycling, 1970-1977 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Bleeding foot manuscript, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Body asymmetry and short-leg syndrome, 1960-1978 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Body Size - References, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Bone, 1948-1954 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Booklet "Anatomy of a Headache", 1984 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Brain Circulation, 1956-1957 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Breathing, 1969 -1975 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Burns experiments, 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Calcium Metabolism, 1963-1971 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Calf Pain, 1952-1956 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Carbon Tetrachloride, 1935-1940 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cardiac and Somatic Chest Pain - Case Reports, 1940ca. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cardiac Arrest, 1950-1958 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cardiac Arrhythmias, 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cardiac Effects of Nicotine, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cardiac Pain, 1953-1960 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case report - leg pain, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case report - leg pain, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case report - leg pain, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case report - leg pain, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case reports - leg pain, 1951-1952 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case Reports and Paper on Postural Vertigo (with Virginia Davidson Weeks, M.D., Dr. Travell's niece), 1950ca. (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case Reports, 1954-1958 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Case Reports, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Catecholamines, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cellular Effects - Collagen, 1955-1971 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cervical Root Syndrome, 1948-1968 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Chart Revision - Cornell, 1940-1941 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Chest Pain, 1940-1960 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Chicago Veterans administration Hospital lecture notes, 04/28/1969 -04/29/1969 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Chiropractic, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Chiropractors, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cholesterol, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cold Pain threshold, 1950 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Comparison of recovery curves on wood and skin after freon and ethyl chloride spray experiments, 1955 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Comprehensive Care Demonstration, 01/22/1960 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Copper, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cornell University Medical College, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Correspondence on Quadratus Lumborum, 1971-1977 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Correspondence - Hiccups, 1977-1981 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Correspondence - Dulcolax drug, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Coxsackie virus, 1952 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Cranio-Fascial Pain Center study group, 10/05/1981 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Creatine References, 1950-1951 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Curare drugs, 1939-1957 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Curare, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Curare, Cocaine, Procaine treatments, 1949-1959 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Dental References, 1933-1959 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Digitalis, 1927-1948 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Dissertations on Men and Medicine, 1923-1953 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Dizziness, 1940-1972 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Dolorimeter pricking pain measuring device, 1953 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Dr. Baker - ischemic muscle pain, 1950ca. (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Drugs which depress diarrhea, nausea, and vomiting, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Early papers of Dr. Janet Travell, 1940-1954 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Early Relief of Chest Pain by Ethyl Chloride Spray in Acute Coronary Thrombosis" by Janet Travell, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Effect of sustained pressure on trigger areas, 1942 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Effects of ergonovine on the heart, 1956 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Effects of ergonovine on the isolated Atherosclerotic Heart of the Cholesterol-fed rabbit, 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Effects of stretch on muscle, 1954-1961 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Elbow Pain treated by Ethyl Chloride Spray, 1950 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Elbow pain, 1948-1952 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Electrocardiography, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Electromyograph Experiments, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Eli Lilly Research Laboratory Talks, 10/1949 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Entrapment Syndrome, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Environment - Rachel Carson, 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ergometric Studies - Calf, 1951 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ethyl Chloride Spray - General Clinical Uses, 1948-1959 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Excretion - Oxalic, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Exercise, 1934-1970 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Exercise - Bonnie Prudden, 1969-1975 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Exercise - Heart & Circulation, 1960-1971 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Exercises, 1961-1963 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: "Factors Affecting Pain of Injection" by Janet Travell, 1955 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Fibrostitic syndrome, 1946-1958 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Folic Acid, 1970-1975 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Film on "Myofascial Genesis of Pain,", 1950 -1951 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Fitness for Young Families book, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Foot development, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Foot Stools, 1952-1971 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Freon Experiments, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Gamma Globulins, 1962-1964 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Gebauer Chemical Company, 1957-1960 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Reports, Subject Research: General Cardiac Problems, 1930-1955 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Reports, Subject Research: General Chemical Division, Allied Chemical & Dye Co., 1950-1960 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Reports, Subject Research: General lecture notes, 1957-1984 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Reports, Subject Research: General Sternomastoid - with data charts, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Geriatrics, 1959-1962 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Groin Pain, 1946-1949 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: G.W. Vascular Clinic, Reprints, Notes, 1962-1970 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Headache and Dizziness, 1962-1979 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Headache and Face Pain, 1944-1945 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Headache, 1944-1967 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Herpes experiments, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Herpes simplex, 1957-1976 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Hiccups, 1969-1977 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Hiccups, 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Histamine, 1940-1948 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: How to give Painless Injections, 1947 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Hyaluronidase Experiments, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Hyaluronidase, 1949-1953 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Hypnosis, 1954-1957 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Hypometabolism, 1955-1957 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Illustrations of muscles and pain points, 1950ca. (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Intermittent Claudication Abstract (American Heart Association), 04/08/1953 -04/12/1953 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ischemia and Burns and Spray, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ischemic Forearm Contraction tests, 1950ca. (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Ischemic Pain Tests, 1948 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Janet Travell - Creatine tolerance tests, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Janet Travell and John Mendell - Vapocoolant Spray and Pain Relief, 1973-1987 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Jaw - reading, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Jaw Aperture Data, 1944-1955 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Jaw Pain case reports, 1957-1971 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Joint Paper on Myofascial Pain with Robert D. Gerwin, for journal Pain Management (3-part series), and correspondence, 1986-1990 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Joint Paper on Myofascial Pain with Robert D. Gerwin, for journal Pain Management (3-part series), 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation Progress Reports, 1954-1958 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation research, 1951-1958 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Jump Rope, 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Kennedy Foundation grant application, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Krebiozen, 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    General note
    See Placebos
  - Reports, Subject Research: Laboratories for Mental Retardation correspondence of visiting committee for the Joseph P. Kennedy Laboratory for Mental Retardation, 1959-1960 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Lack of Exercise, 1962-1975 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Latissimus Dorsi paper with David Simons, 11/08/1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Leg and Foot Pain, 1944-1954 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Leg length inequality, 1960-1971 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Licorice, 1946-1967 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Linus Pauling - Vitamin C, 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Reports, Subject Research: List of medical films, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Low Back Pain, 1952-1959 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Low Back Pain, Sciatica, Sacroiliac, 1939-1953 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Lying Down, 1969-1971 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Magnesium and Calcium Determinations, 1957-1959 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manipulation - References, 1951-1967 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript - "Management of Skeletal Pain", 1959 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Reports, Subject Research: Manuscript "Role of Somatic Trigger Areas in the Patterns of Hysteria," (et al), 1948 (Box 23, Folder 17)